A Guide to the Mathews (Va.) Records, 1792-1952
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Mathews County (Va.) Records, 1792-1952
The Library of Virginia
1006114-1208353 circa
30 boxes and or volumes
Mathews County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Mathews County including a shipment under accession number 21813.
Historical Information
Mathews County was named for Thomas Mathews, of Norfolk, the Speaker of the Virginia House of Delegates in 1790 when the county was formed from Gloucester County.
Scope and Content
Mathews County (Va.) Records, 1792-1952, include various records from the following series: Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Board of Supervisors' Records, Business Records, Court Records, Election Records, Fiduciary Records, Land Records, Marriage Records, Miscellaneous Records, Organization Records, Public Building and Grounds, Road and Bridge Records, School Records, and Tax and Fiscal Records, Town Administrative Records, and Wills.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Mathews County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm"
Related Material
Mathews County is one of Virginia's Lost Records Localities. Additional Mathews County Court Records may be found in the Virginia Lost Records Localities Collection at the Library of Virgina. Search the Lost Records Localities Database found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Mathews County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Mathews County.
Geographical Names:
Mathews County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Mathews County.
Added Entry - Corporate Name:
Mathews County (Va.) Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.
Contents List
- Records, 1842-1904
  Accounts; Oaths; Bonds; Commonwealth Causes
- Records, 1891-1950
  Clerk's Correspondence; Oyster Inspector Reports
- Records, 1867-1886
  Oyster Inspector Reports
- Records 1887-1889
- Records, 1885-1903
  Powers of Attorney; Petitions and Applications; Oyster Inspector Reports
- Records, undated
  Unidentified Index and Lists
- Records 1870-1902
  Lists of Writings Admitted; Glebe Interest; Enumeration
- Records 1882-1940
  Fiduciaries; License Not Liquor; Merchant Licenses; Liquor Law; Taxes Assessed; Personal Property Taxes; Reassessments of Lands
- Records 1824-1904
  Criminal Warrants; Warrant Executions; Recognizances; Warrants of Arrest; Commssions of Justices
- Records 1870-1904
  Plats and Oyster Plats; List of Voters; Register of Marriages
- Records 1893-1952
  Plat of Jesse Miller's Land; Plats of Oyster Area Mobjack Bay; Other Plats; Blueprints of Side Wheel Steamer
- Records 1857, 1794
  Register of Marriages; Tax Book
- Records 1838-1887
  Personal Property and Land Book; Poll Book
- Records 1860-1904
  Glebe Interest; Miscellaneous Bonds; Dutton Brothers. Vouchers; Mobjack Transportation Company Minutes
- Records 1796-1945; undated
  Clerk's Correspondence; Clerk's Fees; Commissioners' Reports; County Court Dockets; Court Finance; Criminal Pardons; Executions; Fragments; Jury Certificates
- Records 1844-1904
  Estate papers; Administrator/Guardian/Executor Records; Orders; Settlements of Estates; Trustee appointments; Coroner's Inquisitions; Smallpox epidemic papers; Deeds; Bills of sale of enrolled vessels; Lists of Conveyances; Miscellaneous land records (petitions for wharf, reservation of title, petitions to open oyster beds, land purchase report and survey, application to purchase delinquent lands); Marriage License Authorizations; Applications for military pension; Lists of expenses incurred since the close of the war (Civil War); ;Act of Assembly; Glass plate negative of unknown woman; Mechanics liens; Powers of Attorney; Resolutions; Appointment of new trustees; Overseer of the Poor Records
- Records 1844-1902; undated
  Board of Supervisors Records; Apllication for certificate to practice law; Appointments of Officials; Oaths of Office; Officials' bonds; Officials' resignations; Petitions to appoint/remove oyster inspectors; Removal of officials; Treasurers bonds; Corporations/Partnerships: Contract; Insurance Policies; Abstract of Minute Book; Attorney's memorandums; Bonds and Accounts; Chancery fees; Chancery warrants; Clerk's Records: Clerk's correspondence
- Records, 1803-1901
  Courthouse/jail inspections/repairs; School commissioners accounts; School commissioners reports; Township Records; Wills; Wrappers
- Records, 1848-1950 circa
  Executions; Page from fee book; Index to unidentified docket book; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Election Records; Unidentified lawyer's notes
- Records 1814-1908
  Deeds; Deeds and Contracts; Land Alterations; Processioners' Report; Militia District No. 1 Records; Justice of the Peace Commissions; Court Records; Petitions of Widows and Orphans for Support Under the State Law; List of Military Pensioners; Act of 1900 and 1902; Lists of Indigent Soldiers(Civil War); Applications for Military Pensions; Applications for Exemption From Military Duty (Civil War); Lane Diggs Camp Correspondence; United Confederate Veterans Correspondence; Sands Smith Correspondence
- Records, 1871-1903
  Surveyor of Road Appointments, Reports, Accounts; Road Cases Disposed Of; Road Surveys, Reports, and Petitions; Marriage Licenses to be Recorded; Marriage License; Notices of Candidacy
- Records, 1880-1906
  Road Petitions and Applications; Road Reports
- Records, 1861-1903
  Road and Bridge Records Claims; Orders; Overseer/Surveyor Appointments and Resignations; Road Fines; Road Petitions and Applications
- Records, 1918-1936
  Correspondence to the Mathews Journal newspaper concerning World War I service; Mathews Baseball Club Correspondence
- Records, 1884-1920
  Improper Assessment of Land; Reassessments; Lists of Oyster Planters
- Records, 1870-1901
  List of Real Estate; Delinquent Lands; Improper Assessments
- Records, 1854-1902; undated
  Delinquent Tax Lists; Licenses; Liquor Bonds; Oyster Law Taxes; Requests for Reassessment; Sheriff's Accounts; Tax Exemptions; Treasurer's Records
- Records, 1859-1903; undated
  Commonwealth Claims; County Bonds; County Claims; Delinquent Land Lists
- Records, 1792-1901
  Reports to Clerk; Returns of Sale of Delinquent Lands
- Records, 1882-1932
  Road Warrants; Jury Claims; Revenue Returns; Warrants; Receipts and Dispursements